{"1": {"question": "Who invented the pianoforte?", "correct": "Bartolommeo Cristofori", "incorrect": ["Adolphe Sax", "Ferdinando de' Medici", "Leonardo da Vinci"]}, "2": {"question": "The Clavichord was the favourite instrumet of which famous composer?", "correct": "Bach", "incorrect": ["Mozart", "Beethoven", "Handel"]}, "3": {"question": "The harpsichord was a double what?", "correct": "Spinet", "incorrect": ["Clavichord", "Pianoforte", "Big mac"]}, "4": {"question": "Who composed Solfeggietto?", "correct": "C.P.E. Bach", "incorrect": ["Beethoven", "Mozart", "Haydn"]}, "5": {"question": "Who composed Rondo in B minor?", "correct": "C.P.E. Bach", "incorrect": ["Weber", "Mozart", "Schubert"]}, "6": {"question": "Who composed Variations in F minor?", "correct": "Haydn", "incorrect": ["Mozart", "Beethoven", "Mendelssohn"]}, "7": {"question": "Who composed Fantasia in C major (Capriccio)?", "correct": "Haydn", "incorrect": ["C.P.E. Bach", "Handel", "Liszt"]}, "8": {"question": "Who composed the Sonata in D for two pianos?", "correct": "Mozart", "incorrect": ["Haydn", "C.P.E. Bach", "Beethoven"]}, "9": {"question": "Who composed Invitation to the Waltz?", "correct": "Weber", "incorrect": ["Schubert", "Schumann", "Chopin"]}, "10": {"question": "Who composed Fantasia in C major (Wanderer)?", "correct": "Schubert", "incorrect": ["Weber", "Haydn", "Bach"]}, "11": {"question": "Who composed the Hungarian Rhapsodies?", "correct": "Liszt", "incorrect": ["C.P.E. Bach", "Chopin", "Schumann"]}, "12": {"question": "Who composed Mendelssohn's CharacterstÃ¼cke?", "correct": "Mendelssohn", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Liszt", "You are so small brain"]}, "13": {"question": "Who composed the Variations and Fugue on Theme of Handel?", "correct": "Brahms", "incorrect": ["Haydn", "Handel", "Debussy"]}, "14": {"question": "Who composed the Rhapsody on a theme of Paganini?", "correct": "Rachmaninoff", "incorrect": ["Shostakovich", "Bartok", "Prokofiev"]}, "15": {"question": "Who composed Rhapsody in blue?", "correct": "Gershwin", "incorrect": ["De Falla", "Weber", "Schumann"]}, "16": {"question": "Who composed Sonatina Op. 13?", "correct": "Kabalevsky", "incorrect": ["Shostakovich", "Paganini", "Telemann"]}, "17": {"question": "Who composed Three Fantastic Dances?", "correct": "Shostakovich", "incorrect": ["Gershwin", "Rachmaninoff", "Putin"]}, "18": {"question": "Who composed Variations on a Theme by Paganini?", "correct": "Brahms", "incorrect": ["Paganini", "Ravel", "Rachmaninoff"]}, "19": {"question": "Who composed Polichinelle?", "correct": "Rachmaninoff", "incorrect": ["Ravel", "Chopin", "Brahms"]}, "20": {"question": "Who composed Tombeau de Couperin?", "correct": "Ravel", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Schumann", "Mozart"]}, "21": {"question": "Who composed Gaspard de la nuit?", "correct": "Ravel", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Brahms", "Schubert"]}, "22": {"question": "Who composed almost a thousand works including the best studies ever written?!?!?!?!?!? ðŸ˜±ðŸ˜±ðŸ˜±", "correct": "Czerny", "incorrect": ["Liszt", "Ravel", "Schumann"]}, "23": {"question": "Who wrote over 30 chamber works and the spirits of him dwells in them, for they are full of his magic melody lines - they was the greatest melodic genius the world has ever known. They was also a master of harmony and their adventurous harmony is the most striking feature of his chamber works. He, like Beethoven, had a strong sense of tonality, and at times has some entrancing changes of key. He was especially fond of changing the mode from major to minor or vice versa on the same tonic and also liked an abrupt change to a key a major 3rd below the tonic. Some of the most wonderful and widely-loved chamber works in all of music were written by this great composer?", "correct": "Schubert", "incorrect": ["Jesus", "Liszt", "Haydn"]}, "24": {"question": "Who composed Piano Quintet Op. 34?", "correct": "Brahms", "incorrect": ["Schumann", "Schubert", "Haydn"]}, "25": {"question": "Who composed Emperor Quartet?", "correct": "Haydn", "incorrect": ["Bach", "Beethoven", "Handel"]}, "26": {"question": "Who composed Barcarolle in F# minor?", "correct": "Chopin", "incorrect": ["Ravel", "Schumann", "Schubert"]}, "27": {"question": "The name Ballades first came into Piano music with which composer?", "correct": "Chopin", "incorrect": ["Haydn", "Field", "Handel"]}, "28": {"question": "Which composer wrote almost only for the piano?", "correct": "Chopin", "incorrect": ["Schumann", "Mozart", "Bach"]}, "29": {"question": "Which word is derived from the traditional song of Venetian gondoliers?", "correct": "Barcarolle", "incorrect": ["Ballades", "Mazurkas", "Polonaises"]}, "30": {"question": "What time signature is Chopin's Barcarolle in?", "correct": "12/8", "incorrect": ["6/8", "3/8", "7/8"]}, "31": {"question": "What is an etude?", "correct": "A study or technical exercise", "incorrect": ["Lively, loosely structured piece that is often humourous in character", "Any piece of music that is sung", "An instrumental musical form introduced in the Baroque period"]}, "32": {"question": "Who composed the Revolutionary Etude?", "correct": "Chopin", "incorrect": ["Haydn", "Mozart", "Brahms"]}, "33": {"question": "What does Scherzo mean?", "correct": "Joke", "incorrect": ["Frenzy", "Sudden", "Song"]}, "34": {"question": "To Chopin the title '________' embraced a multiplicity of contrasting musical ideas with alternating episodes of explosive passion and lyrically serene melody.", "correct": "Scherzo", "incorrect": ["Sonata", "Polonaise", "Impromptu"]}, "35": {"question": "At what age did Chopin compose his first sonata?", "correct": "18", "incorrect": ["21", "44", "6"]}, "36": {"question": "What is a polonaise?", "correct": "One of the national dances of Poland", "incorrect": ["A burger sauce", "A Polish military song", "A piece played before another piece/play/ceremony"]}, "37": {"question": "Which composer had a lamed hand?", "correct": "Schumann", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Mozart", "Beethoven"]}, "38": {"question": "Who composed the 'ABEGG' Theme and Variations?", "correct": "Schumann", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Liszt", "Brahms"]}, "39": {"question": "How many sonatas did Schumann compose?", "correct": "3", "incorrect": ["4", "1", "2"]}, "40": {"question": "What is a novelette?", "correct": "A short piece of lyrical music, especially one for piano", "incorrect": ["A short piece of lyrical music, especially one for vocal", "A long piece of lyrical music, especially one for piano", "A long piece of lyrical music, especially one for vocal"]}, "41": {"question": "What does DavidsbÃ¼ndlertÃ¤nze translate to?", "correct": "Dances of the League of David", "incorrect": ["A group of eighteen pieces for piano", "Dances of David", "It's not a real word"]}, "42": {"question": "Translate Ã‰tudes Symphoniques", "correct": "Symphonic studies", "incorrect": ["Symphonic etudes", "Studies Symphoniques", "I refuse"]}, "43": {"question": "What does Faschingsschwank aus Wien translate to?", "correct": "Carnival jest from Vienna", "incorrect": ["Carnival sausages from Vienna", "Fashion from Vienna", "State government of Vienna"]}, "44": {"question": "Why is Schumann referred to as the founder of the Romantic Period in Music?", "correct": "His creative career coincided with the flowering of Romanticism in paining and literature", "incorrect": ["He ushered in a new style of playing music with elements of the Romantic style", "He possessed the rare gifts of the power of expression - from the humourous element to teh expression of a deep and subtle emotion", "In his music is a fresh, youthful note with heaven-soaring melodies, clashing harmonies and rushing rhythms"]}, "45": {"question": "Who devised the practice of placing the thumb under in scale passages?", "correct": "C.P.E. Bach", "incorrect": ["Mozart", "Beethoven", "Couperin"]}, "46": {"question": "What are Kinderszenen?", "correct": "Scenes from childhood", "incorrect": ["A type of chocolate", "Kindergarten", "Childlike songs"]}, "47": {"question": "What are Waldszenen?", "correct": "Woodland Scenes", "incorrect": ["Waltz songs", "Waltz Scenes", "Woodland songs"]}, "48": {"question": "What are Papillons?", "correct": "Butterflies", "incorrect": ["Papers", "Pepe", "Butter fingers"]}, "49": {"question": "What are Schumann's Kreisleriana?", "correct": "A set of eight fantasy pieces dedicated to Chopin", "incorrect": ["A set of six fantasy pieces dedicated to Chopin", "His signature cookies", "A set of eight fantasy pieces dedicated to Liszt"]}, "50": {"question": "Who? ", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["Maybe", "Them", "Same"]}, "51": {"question": "Who composed 'Coloured Leaves'?", "correct": "Schumann", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Debussy", "Beethoven"]}, "52": {"question": "Who composed the FantasiestÃ¼cke called 'Why'?", "correct": "Schumann", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Debussy", "Mozart"]}, "53": {"question": "Which composer was a cheeky bugger?", "correct": "Schumann, for playing a slightly disguised form of a fragment of 'Marseillaise', a piece banned in Vienna", "incorrect": ["Beethoven, for composing the Amongus imposter theme", "Debussy, for composing Claire de Lune", "Tchaikovsky, for referencing 'La Marseillaise' in the 1812 Overture"]}, "54": {"question": "For how many hands were Schumann's piano duets composed?", "correct": "4", "incorrect": ["2", "3", "6"]}}